When working with Word documents, there
may be occasions where you need to
insert information in a table format.
There are two ways of doing
this within Word, and the first
way is quite straightforward.
So if I go up to the insert tab and I
selected insert, and then on the table
icon, selected insert table, I can
then create a table with the number and
columns and rows that I would require.
So as long as I knew how many columns
and rows I needed, I could insert that.
I just select that as an example.
And as you can see, it is inserted
five columns and six rows.
The problem there is I still need to
populate the table with the information
so if I just undo that by Command and Z.
An alternative to that is to
actually import the information
and format it as a table.
So I have the information
that I wish to enter into the
letter within this spreadsheet.
So I'm just going to highlight the
information and use Command and C to copy.
And then once I've copied that
I can go back to the letter and
place the cursor where I want the
information to be entered, and
then I will use the Command and V.
So as you can see that has now pasted
the the information into the letter,
but it's pretty much in the same format
as it was within the spreadsheet.
So it doesn't look very presentable.
There are a number of paste
options, and you'll see that by
the little clipboard at the bottom.
So if I click on that, I can keep the
source formatting which is what it's
doing at the moment, match destination
table style, paste as a picture, keep
the text only, keep source formatting
and link it to Excel, so it would look
the same, but it would be linked to
the spreadsheet, match destination
table, style and link to Excel.
So that would put it into a
table within the document and
then still link it to Excel.
So that meant that if any of
the data changed within the
spreadsheet, it would then update
in the table within the letter.
So for this example, I'm just going to
keep the text only so I can demonstrate
how you can convert text to a table.
So I'll keep the text and as you can
see, it doesn't look very presentable
and it's not very well laid out.
So what I need to do is I now need to
highlight all of that information and
then go up to the insert tab and select
table, and then convert text to table.
So if I click on that now, it will ask
me how many columns and rows I want.
So it actually knows there are three
columns and eight rows required
because it's already worked it out.
And the column width is
auto and it is separated.
Text at tabs.
That basically means that in between
each of these instances, there is
a tab symbol and just to show that
if I click cancel, and I go to the
home menu and then select the show
hide button from the paragraph tools.
As you can see, there's a little
tab icon in between each of those.
That is what's allowing us to identify
that it is three columns and eight rows.
So if I just take that back off there,
go back to the insert table, convert
text to table, three columns, eight
rows, separated by tabs, click OK.
And that has created a table
with the information included.
So from there, when I'm on the
actual table design tab, I can then
change the style so I can apply
different table styles to the table.
I can expand that so I can have
a wider range of table styles.
So I'll just for example, select that one.
And again, if I want to make any more
changes, just double click on the
table, you could add shading, border
styles, different pen colors, and
line widths, and various other things
that you may wish to experiment with.
But that is how you can insert a
table from Excel into a document and
format it to make it look presentable.